hey everybody everybody in the world who
invents things tried them at the
telephone and we'll buy it from you so
this inventor Alexander Graham Bell is
like oh sh invent the telephone yes
please
[Music]
hello
today we're going to talk about the
invention of Coca-Cola America's
favorite soft drink
[Music]
so like in the 1800s John Pemberton was
trying to make patent medicines
basically they were fake medicines and
most of them were just like herbal who's
he what's who even cares he was just
trying to make anything that would sell
he was like I want to make a fake
medicine that made women think that
they'll never be nervous or have farts
[Music]
and make men think that they can be
smarter so he decided to use a new
ingredient Coca
coca is from a plant the South Americans
would chew it and be like we had so much
energy and we weren't even hungry and we
hiked the whole Andes but really they
were just on cocaine John Pemberton was
like oh I should put this into my new
potion that I'm making and basically he
copied someone else's recipe called like
Vin
Mariani he was like well I have wine I
put Coca in there a little of this Cola
in the cola nut release a little bit of
caffeine
and he he basically was like what I give
you is a wine with cocaine caffeine then
people in Atlanta were like no nobody
cannot sell alcohol because of
temperance
he was like okay well fine I'll just
make a Temperance beverage he went back
into his laboratory and he decided to
just put the Coca and the cola
together but they were super bitter
without the wine so we added a ton of
sugar and then he made it into like a
drink you know he thought oh well people
will love this it wasn't like he was
like I made a soda because nobody even
had that yet he had a friend named Frank
Robinson
who was like okay well I'll help you to
sell your um medicine soda drink thingy
first of all you should
um change the K in the cola to a c and
and just call it what it is Coca Cola
and the two C's will look really nice
next to each other and who wouldn't love
that
so they would just advertise Coca-Cola
as a medicine for your brain they would
say it's invigorating and stimulating
and healthy for your nervous system
using the Exotic extract of the Coca and
cola nut
to make you super alive and ready to
face your day
[Music]
the first year
you only sold 25 gallons
25 000 or 25 25 gallons okay in the year
he gave it to pharmacies they had like a
soda fountains and fun things and people
did like it a lot oh this is like a
great drink they thought that it made
them like invigorated and aware people
are basically drinking little cocaine
soda me me me me me me me I need more I
wish I was alive then to drink the cocoa
Coca-Cola
[Music]
uh
God I missed so much from not being in
the old 10 times
[Music]
the next year
he sold 200 gallons a month
that's so much more 12 months
[Music]
Reggie stop it
well
Reggie God damn it hold on
okay I got him
12 months out of the year we sold 2 000
gallons a month no yes
he's on his deathbed dying his stomach
cancer
and he's like out of all of the patent
medicines that I've tried to make I've
finally made a successful patent
medicine but what he never knew was that
he actually made the most successful
drink that humans will ever drink ever
God he was so successful and he doesn't
know and he'll never know ever they
still
use coca leaves in modern day Coca-Cola
do the math on that one even if they
don't have cocaine in them they still
use the leaves and they took the cocaine
out
putting it somewhere else
welcome to drunkest room JB Risner today
we're gonna tell us worry about the
invasion of the telephone
our story starts in the 1870s where the
Telegraph Corporation Western Union and
Western Union was starting to go like
all right the telegraph is fine but like
what's next
so they're like we're looking for
somebody to invent a way to like talk
your voice over a wire to some other
dude it's a wonderful thing where you
call people's homes and this is
telephone now there's a dude whose name
is Alicia pronounced Elisha Elisha gray
sold Telegraph Parts it's like I invent
little Telegraph things I am a cute
little inventor I'm Elisha gray so
Western Union is like Elisha gray invent
the telephone lash gray is like great
the Western Union goes to the public
it's like hey everybody everybody in the
world who invents things tried them at
the telephone and we'll buy it from you
so this inventor Alexander Graham Bell
is like oh sh invent the telephone yes
please
we're doing good we're really drunk
so Alexander Graham Bell gets to work
trying to remember the telephone he's
having a hard time he can't figure it
out like it's kind of me talking but I
sound like a robot Alexander Graham
Bell's lawyers are like this is a
telephone you're not doing a good job
Alexander Graham Bell
so his lawyer goes to the patent clerk
at the U.S patent office Zenus Fisk
Wilbur
it's a weird old name it's the insurance
penis that's how I remember it Zenus
the guy had all sorts of Pros was a
drunkard like I'm poor and I'm drunk and
I'm depressed Graham Bell's lawyer said
listen you owe us money why if anybody
submits telephone pad let me know
meanwhile Elijah gray is like having the
same problems Alexander Graham Bell was
having he was like I'm talking on the
phone how can I make this electric
current be smoother on the other end
what if I put a little water in the dude
dad the water vibrates in more subtler
tones and that goes through the wire and
it's clear as cell Bonanza so it goes to
the patent office and he files a pen I
know how to make the telephone but this
is how I'm gonna do it so sure enough
Zenith Fisk Wilbur at the patent office
calls out into grandville's lawyers none
of the telephone because it's not
invented yet but a telegraph or
something he's like hey
somebody just submitted the patent for
the telephone
Alexander Graham Bell goes to the patent
office and goes
what's up Zenith Fisk Wilbur
um okay
jeez sorry about that and then he
swallowed it of course I swallowed what
I'm gonna do is spit it on the floor
maybe you can give me a little something
something about what's going on with
this other guy who filed a patent huh
it's like all right well here it is
here's the drawing of uh oh he's gonna
invent the telephone Alexander Graham
Bell copies down Gray's design it turns
it in meanwhile Elijah great all of a
sudden he hears hey everybody in America
Alexander Graham Bell just invented the
telephone
[Music]
there's a dispute now everybody's like
hey who did it first who who was first
guess who the patent office put in
charge of the investigation Venus Fisk
Wilbur himself and so Alexander Graham
Bell's lawyers are like listen let's
freaking
just let Alexander Graham Bell's patent
come first like what's up so he's like
guess what Alexander Graham Bell you
invented the telephone you win woohoo
Alexander Graham Bell goes off and
builds the first telephone off of Gray's
plans meanwhile Elijah gray is busy
fighting it in court I invented the
telephone it was me this is this is
garbage he copied me and even though he
got Zenus welber to testify in court
like listen I took a bunch of money from
Bell's lawyer so he can invent telephone
and that's the truth still Alexander
Graham Bell is so well known at this
point that Supreme Court's like
Alexander Graham Bell wins and he's the
investment telephone forever well good
work
and then Elijah gray is like oh God I
guess I didn't invent telephones I did
but like I lose anyway what's his name
um how do you remember his name oh
what's his name what's the other guy's
name Wilbur no Walt Disney no
telephone
meanwhile Alexander Graham Bell went on
to make 1800s equivalent of billions off
the telephone and then it was like uh I
made the belt company
I don't care I don't I'm I don't even
like telephones I don't even want one in
my office
that's what a shitty snob Alexander
Graham Bell was meanwhile who uses the
Alexander Graham Bell Telephone anymore
nobody except old people
and poor people
hello
my name is Patrick Brewster and I'm
talking to you today oh my God
you guys ready
are you all done shut your mouth you
ready I'll do it but shush it
hello
hello my name is Paget Brewster and
today we're talking about Mary Phelps
Jacob the inventor of the bra
in 1910 women were cinched in to Tiny
corsets all the time but then there is a
19 year old girl Mary Phelps Jacob
setting up to go to a debutant ball and
she is like ah I got this beautiful silk
dress and I have to put this dumb piece
of on stupid corset with whale bone
inserts uh so goddamn dumb all right I'm
I'm I'm I'm out I'm out I can't take
this Marie mermaid Marie get me two
handkerchiefs some silk cording ribbons
and a sewing kit she sews together two
handkerchiefs onto herself and goes to a
ball
all the girls are like what is going on
with you girl you look better than you
have ever looked and she says yeah I
just
that are some handkerchiefs the girls go
crazy and she's like my bubbles are free
to roam and they all say I want one I
want one I want one all right whatever
I'll make you some I'll make you my new
thing whatever with some handkerchiefs
then she gets a letter in the mail from
someone she's never met saying hey I'll
give you a dollar
to make me a bra and then she realizes
oh this could be a business so she goes
to the patent office and she said hey
I've made this thing it's a Brazier the
patent office guy was like everyone's
had boobs for goddamn forever I
understand that you think you made
something but you didn't and she
said no I did the last piece of patent
flattens your tits into nothing but one
boob do you want one boob and he's like
I don't I can't even I don't even know
if I can answer this no you want two
boobs they separate
and lift give me the patent for the
backless brazier and he says yeah okay
all right I've never seen that I will
give you a patent slam he gives her a
pat
I'm
I'm not gonna throw up but I am I'm
pretty
Gonzo Bonzo
so she opens the fashion form Brazier
company meanwhile she marries this guy
Harry Crosby and Harry says hey babe
because you're going to be my wife
Crosby I feel like you should have a c
name so it's like C Crosby I would
really like it if you change your name
to clitoris
it's true and she says what no
I'm not going to change my name to
clitoris and he's like no it's with a Y
still
sorry I love you man honey but not even
with the why will I name myself clitoris
what about Caress that's better than
clitoris certainly he says to her hey
caress correct she's now caress you're
kind of bored with the bra business and
it's not taking off I'm kind of Rich why
don't you just let it go she says all
right fine she sells her patent to the
Warner Brothers corset company for
fifteen hundred dollars
she's like I'm out I'm good had fun so
wait I have to fast forward
I also have to pee which one you're
gonna do first no I have to pee okay
well then pee I'm gonna
in 1929 the bra took hold everyone
bought bras the corset was dead the
Warner Brothers corset company makes 15
million dollars off of her patent alone
it's a lot of titties I
here's the thing about Mary Phelps Jacob
she never gives she was like oh I'm okay
I sold the patent
not gonna dwell on it I'm gonna open a
publishing company that publishes every
modern writer known to man Hemingway
James Joyce Henry Miller Edgar Allan Poe
of there's so many more someone look it
up on an iPhone you'll see then was
writing pornography for money and she
was great at it and at the end of her
life someone asked her about like hey uh
you invented something
and she said yeah yeah my invention it
wouldn't take the place and history of
something like the steamboat but yeah I
invented the bra
the bra is kind of a big fun deal no one
gives a about a steamboat
do you know anyone who doesn't have a
bra
I do love bras I can see we have lots of
game modes sorry Bros
I didn't want to tell you
my name is Duncan Trussell
and today we're going to talk about
Edison
this story starts in New Jersey with
Thomas Edison one of the great inventors
of the time known as The Wizard of Menlo
Park he would get poor Geniuses gather
them together and he's like just make
stuff for me if it's good I'm gonna say
it's mine whatever you're gonna make
money so just do it
an inventor by the name of my bridge
Camden New Jersey shows this incredible
device he'd managed to take a bunch of
pictures of a horse running and spin
them on a cylinder in a way that gave it
animation and Edison's like you know
great a a horse running cool
invention or whatever bye and then he's
like we gotta figure this
out because people are gonna want to
watch this stuff we got to start working
on this right now and then
in 1893 Edison is like I figured out how
to do it guys I can I can photograph and
make a movie we can make movies now I
came up with the very first camera the
kinetograph and I figured out a way to
look at the strings of moving pictures a
kinetoscope and it's all my idea my idea
you ask people
to your truck
why would I take another drink
so Edison needed content for his
kinetoscopes and everything he was
putting out was he's like let's get
cats boxing man and then
Vaudeville scenes of people chasing each
other let's film a blacksmith shop
everyone's gonna want to see that right
guys right
right and they filmed it people were
into it man freaking out everyone's like
have you been to the Connecticut parlor
oh you've got to go it's incredible so
people came to Edison they're like hey
look what we can do we can project
images on the screen he's like wow
that's amazing I can't believe I
invented that that's incredible I am so
smart let's patent this movies
take off people love it they went to
these places called Nickelodeon's for a
nickel you're in a great theater come on
in people would sit in those theaters
and be like this is awesome it's an
Edison creates an industry town and
everyone comes to Fort Lee to start
making movies and Edison squeezes all of
them he was like join me in what we're
gonna call the Edison trust and all of
you can join together with me
and we're gonna make it so that no other
make movies except us
down in your
neck and everyone's like great let's do
it I don't want you to sue me so I'll
just agree to whatever you say because
you're super rich and I just want to
make art so great
sounds good they created a monopoly on
all filmmaking there was a fella by the
name of Carl Lemley went to one of
Edison's shitty shows it's like that is
so bad people are paying a nickel to
watch this why don't we try to make our
own movies and so Carl Lemley starts
making movies he creates his own theater
and Edison it's like no no I'm sorry
what are you doing you're not allowed to
make movies and you're definitely not
allowed to show movies on my
equipment without paying me a
licensing fee how dare you he sues
limley
284 times lemley's number one dream I
just want to one day make enough money
to take my family on a vacation in
Europe and Edison is like I'm gonna
squash you like a bug I'm the
wizard of Menlo Park take your family on
a vacation up my ass
foreign
oh God he was just he was just eating a
turd in the yard Edison was a bastard
imagine 284 lawsuits man but Lemley was
like
you I'm gonna keep making these movies
and Edison faced with true opposition
started sending thugs to lemley's movie
theaters people are just sitting and
enjoying movies and all of a sudden
Edison thugs would come crashing through
the door and be like off no one's
watching this this is not an
Addison film they would go to the
Productions beat up the actors
but Lemley didn't back down there's
three guys who kept making movies Lemley
Fox and Zucker and finally they realized
what the are we doing in New Jersey
we're shooting films in New Jersey and
on a daily basis getting sued and beaten
up let's get the out of New Jersey
how about we go to Los Angeles
where it's sunny all the time and you
don't get your ass kicked by a dick
that's that makes great sense
that's a great idea
they headed to LA and those three Heroes
created Universal Studios Fox and
Paramount United States government
recognized that the Edison trust was a
monopoly and they broke it up uh sorry
Edison you can't have control over all
film being made in the world if we let
you have your way then people would be
looking at cats boxing until the planet
blew up you
you're trying to ruin your species you
don't even realize it you greedy
reptilian bag
still people are going to think you're
great though No One's Gonna know so
congratulations demon
[Music]
please don't don't deserve to be
rewarded for their inventions instead of
suing people you work with them and then
the end result of that is the entire
planet wakes up we experience what's
called The Singularity everybody gets
dissolved by Nanobots and we are travel
through the universe as infinite beings
of love
[Music]